<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human Pangenome</title>
    <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Human Pangenome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://humanpangenome.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HPRC Publications</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>There are several HPRC publications in development at this time. Please check back for updates and follow us on Twitter @HumanPangenome. Below is a selection of publications from the HPRC membership. The Human Pangenome Project: a global resource to map genomic diversity.
Wang T., Antonacci-Fulton L., Howe K., et al., 2022-04-20
Pangenome-based genome inference allows efficient and accurate genotyping across a wide spectrum of variant classes.
Ebler J, Ebert P, Clarke WE, Rausch T, Audano PA, Houwaart T, Mao Y, Korbel JO, Eichler EE, Zody MC, Dilthey AT, Marschall T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPRC Publications</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/publications_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/publications_old/</guid>
      <description>There are several HPRC publications in development at this time. Please check back for updates and follow us on Twitter @HumanPangenome. Below is a selection of publications from the HPRC membership. The Human Pangenome Project: a global resource to map genomic diversity.
Wang T., Antonacci-Fulton L., Howe K., et al., 2022-04-20
Pangenome-based genome inference allows efficient and accurate genotyping across a wide spectrum of variant classes.
Ebler J, Ebert P, Clarke WE, Rausch T, Audano PA, Houwaart T, Mao Y, Korbel JO, Eichler EE, Zody MC, Dilthey AT, Marschall T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPRC PUBLICATIONS</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:33:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>There are several HPRC publications in development at this time. Please check back for updates and follow us on Twitter @HumanPangenome. Below is a selection of publications from the HPRC membership. The Human Pangenome Project: a global resource to map genomic diversity.
Wang T., Antonacci-Fulton L., Howe K., et al., 2022-04-20
Pangenome-based genome inference allows efficient and accurate genotyping across a wide spectrum of variant classes.
Ebler J, Ebert P, Clarke WE, Rausch T, Audano PA, Houwaart T, Mao Y, Korbel JO, Eichler EE, Zody MC, Dilthey AT, Marschall T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/about-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/about-us/</guid>
      <description>OVERVIEW The National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI) is funding multiple components to improve and update the Human Genome Reference Program. These funding resources include the following: A Human Genome Reference Center (HGRC; RFA-HG-19-004), High Quality Human Reference Genomes (HGRQ; RFA-HG-19-002), Genome Reference Representations (GRR; RFA-HG-19-003), Informatics tools for use of the human genome reference (see Concept documents), Technology development for complete sequencing of genomes (NOT-HG-19-011).
The Human Pangenome Reference Center (HPRC)s The Human Pangenome Reference Center (HPRC) at Washington University will serve as the coordinating center for the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium Organization</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/consortium/</guid>
      <description>This is the current infrastructure of the organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Board</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>Bob Waterston, MD, PhD Bob Waterston, MD, PhD, is a Professor of Genome Sciences and Medical Genetics at University of Washington where he was the Department Chair of Genome Sciences from 2002 to 2019. His research includes working with the Sanger Institute to complete the first genomic sequence of C. elegans. These efforts were followed by his work on the Human Genome Project, which was completed in April 2003. At UW, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/partners/</guid>
      <description>Coriell Institute Many of the samples used in the reference genome are made available to researchers through the Coriell Institute.
Genome Reference Consortium Helps to put nucleotide sequences into chromosome context for many different genomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Members</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/associate-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/associate-members/</guid>
      <description>Human Pangenome Reference Consortium is an international effort focused on developing an inclusive collection of human reference genomes that represent human haplotype diversity and the tool ecosystem needed to fully utilize this resource. The consortium welcomes the participation of all additional academic, industry partners and non-profit organizations. The value for these members is a highly interactive research environment that involves many aspects of the Human Pangenome Reference Research.
Data Availability – All data contributed to or generated by the HPRC will be made publicly available for research purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPRC Commitment</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/committment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/committment/</guid>
      <description>The Human Pangenome Project aims to improve the human reference genome to represent a collection of common haplotypes in human populations, with a pangenome reference assembly that reflects genomic diversity across the globe. As such HPRC has commited to the Global Alliance for Genomics and Health (GA4GH) mission and principles and supports its Framework for Responsible Sharing of Genomic and Health-Related Data and aims to adopt GA4GH deliverables where appropriate. Learn more in the GA4GH startup guide and get started as an active contributor in the GA4GH community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Response</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/covid/</guid>
      <description>HPRC members who are able to remain focused on this research will continue to engage in the following activities.
Policy and Administration Development of HPRC protocols and policy will continue as needs are identified. In the coming days, a policy for data use and publications will be released. Sample Selection and Diversity Researchers will continue to engage and discuss diversity in the context of sample selection in order to meet the aims of this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Racism</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/racism/</guid>
      <description>We call for an end to the systemic racism that has killed and oppressed people of color for centuries. While the primary focus has been on reforming institutions such as policing, education, and law, we know that systemic racism also affects genomics and medicine. One of the aims of the Human Pangenome Reference Consortium (HPRC) is to help address the racial and ethnic biases in genomic resources, most specifically in the human reference genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1 Sequencing Data Release</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/year-1-sequencing-data-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/year-1-sequencing-data-release/</guid>
      <description>Human Pangenome Reference Consortium Announced Global Release Of Year 1 Sequencing Data Overview: Researchers from the Human Pangenome Reference Consortium announce the open access publication of Year 1 Sequencing data from 30 samples, representing the first major data release from this project. In addition to data produced as part of the HPRC, the release includes data from over 15 additional samples produced outside of the HPRC.
Sequencing Data Production Centers and Industry partners included the following: PacBio Hifi Data Produced By UW and WashU with support from PacBio Hi-C Sequencing Data Produced By UCSC Strand-Seq Data Produced By EMBL Oxford Nanopore Data Produced By UCSC BioNano Data Produced By Rockefeller Karyotypes &amp;amp; Cell Line Microarray Data Produced By Coriell and CHOP HPRC members selected samples for this study based on adding diversity to the current human reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Data Resources</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/additional-data-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/additional-data-resources/</guid>
      <description>Pangenome Resources @ GitHutb </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Use Protocol</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/data-use-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/data-use-protocol/</guid>
      <description>HPRC goals are to develop resources for the human pangenome. These resources will include high-quality reference genomes, a pangenome tool ecosystem along with annotation of the pangenome reference. Investigators accessing the HPRC data for their research are encouraged to collaborate with the HPRC consortium whenever possible. Please visit the HPRC web site for additional information.
Specific resource sharing plans are maintained by funded investigators of the HPRC and those plans follow the guidelines found at the following link: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HG002</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/hg002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/hg002/</guid>
      <description>The Human Pangenome Reference Consortium asked the scientific community to submit assemblies for the HG002 assembly comparision project.
Background: The Human Reference Pangenome Consortium has organized a collection of HG002 (NA24385) data to guide the development of new assembly and evaluation strategies for our reference production efforts.
We accepted assembly submissions for evaluation until March 16, 2020.
Details below. Please contact Karen Miga (khmiga@soe.ucsc.edu) and Erich Jarvis (ejarvis@rockefeller.edu) for details about submitted assemblies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPRC Year 1 Data Production</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/hpcs-year-1-data-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/hpcs-year-1-data-production/</guid>
      <description>HPRC Data Production for Year is complete with data in QC and assembly. Data release expected in November of 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPRC Publication Protocol</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/hprc-publication-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/blog/hprc-publication-protocol/</guid>
      <description>Publication Protocol – V1.0 | April 7, 2020
The goal of the HPRC publication policy is to encourage collaboration and coordination among investigators while ensuring the timely release of research to the scientific community. The document provides general guidelines and a description of the process for disclosure of planned publications within the consortium through submission. This policy will be drafted and updated by the HPRC Administration and Coordination Working Group and approved by the HPRC steering committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awardees</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/test/yo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/test/yo/</guid>
      <description>Characterization Awards Awardee Institution Title Award Number Jay Shenduree, Nadav Ahituv, Martin Kircher University of Washington, UC San Francisco, Charite Universitatsmedizin Berlin Massively parallel characterization of variants and elements impacting transcriptional regulation in dynamic cellular systems HG011966 Lea Starita, Douglas Fowler University of Washington The Center for Actionable Variant Analysis; measuring variant function at scale HG011969 Jesse Engreitz, Thomas Quertermous Stanford University Stanford Center for Connecting DNA Variants to Function and Phenotype HG011972 Marc Vidal Dana-Farber Cancer Institute Molecular phenotyping of ~100,000 coding variants across Mendelian disease genes HG011989 Gary Hon, William Kraus, Nikhil Munshi University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center Multiscale functional characterization of genomic variation in human developmental disorders HG011996 Hyejung Won, Michael Love, Karen Mohlke University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Systematic in vivo characterization of disease-associated regulatory variants HG012003 Luca Pinello, Daniel Bauer, Guillaume Lettre, Richard Sherwood Massachusetts General Hospital, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, Montreal Heart Institute, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Comprehensive characterization of variants underlying heart and blood diseases with CRISPR base editing HG012010 Charles Gersbach, Gregory Crawford, Tim Reddy Duke University High-throughput functional annotation of gene regulatory elements and variants critical to complex cellular phenotypes HG012053 Mapping Awards Awardee Institution Title Award Number Jason Buenrostro, Bradley Bernstein Broad Institute, Harvard University, Broad Institute, Massachusetts General Hospital A foundational resource of functional elements, TF footprints and gene regulatory interactions HG011986 Ansuman Satpathy Stanford University Single-cell Mapping Center for Human Regulatory Elements and Gene Activity HG012076 Seyed Mortazavi, Barbara Wold UC Irvine, California Institute of Technology Center for Mouse Genomic Variation at Single Cell Resolution HG012077 Predictive Modeling Awards Awardee Institution Title Award Number Alan Boyle University of Michigan Predicting the impact of genomic variation on cellular states HG011952 Andrew S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>To contact us, please fill out the form below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
