<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Human Pangenome</title>
    <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Human Pangenome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/about-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/about-us/</guid>
      <description>OVERVIEW The National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI) is funding multiple components to improve and update the Human Genome Reference Program. These funding resources include the following: A Human Genome Reference Center (HGRC; RFA-HG-19-004), High Quality Human Reference Genomes (HGRQ; RFA-HG-19-002), Genome Reference Representations (GRR; RFA-HG-19-003), Informatics tools for use of the human genome reference (see Concept documents), Technology development for complete sequencing of genomes (NOT-HG-19-011).
The Human Pangenome Reference Center (HPRC)s The Human Pangenome Reference Center (HPRC) at Washington University will serve as the coordinating center for the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium Organization</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/consortium/</guid>
      <description>This is the current infrastructure of the organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Board</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>Bob Waterston, MD, PhD Bob Waterston, MD, PhD, is a Professor of Genome Sciences and Medical Genetics at University of Washington where he was the Department Chair of Genome Sciences from 2002 to 2019. His research includes working with the Sanger Institute to complete the first genomic sequence of C. elegans. These efforts were followed by his work on the Human Genome Project, which was completed in April 2003. At UW, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/partners/</guid>
      <description>Coriell Institute Many of the samples used in the reference genome are made available to researchers through the Coriell Institute.
Genome Reference Consortium Helps to put nucleotide sequences into chromosome context for many different genomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Members</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/associate-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/associate-members/</guid>
      <description>Human Pangenome Reference Consortium is an international effort focused on developing an inclusive collection of human reference genomes that represent human haplotype diversity and the tool ecosystem needed to fully utilize this resource. The consortium welcomes the participation of all additional academic, industry partners and non-profit organizations. The value for these members is a highly interactive research environment that involves many aspects of the Human Pangenome Reference Research.
Data Availability – All data contributed to or generated by the HPRC will be made publicly available for research purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPRC Commitment</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/committment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/committment/</guid>
      <description>The Human Pangenome Project aims to improve the human reference genome to represent a collection of common haplotypes in human populations, with a pangenome reference assembly that reflects genomic diversity across the globe. As such HPRC has commited to the Global Alliance for Genomics and Health (GA4GH) mission and principles and supports its Framework for Responsible Sharing of Genomic and Health-Related Data and aims to adopt GA4GH deliverables where appropriate. Learn more in the GA4GH startup guide and get started as an active contributor in the GA4GH community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Response</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/covid/</guid>
      <description>HPRC members who are able to remain focused on this research will continue to engage in the following activities.
Policy and Administration Development of HPRC protocols and policy will continue as needs are identified. In the coming days, a policy for data use and publications will be released. Sample Selection and Diversity Researchers will continue to engage and discuss diversity in the context of sample selection in order to meet the aims of this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Racism</title>
      <link>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humanpangenome.github.io/products/racism/</guid>
      <description>We call for an end to the systemic racism that has killed and oppressed people of color for centuries. While the primary focus has been on reforming institutions such as policing, education, and law, we know that systemic racism also affects genomics and medicine. One of the aims of the Human Pangenome Reference Consortium (HPRC) is to help address the racial and ethnic biases in genomic resources, most specifically in the human reference genome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
